Guide to the Houston Hip Hop Recording Artists Collection
University of Houston Libraries
Houston Hip Hop Recording Artists Collection
1995-2012
06/2010-009
University of Houston. Libraries. Special Collections Department. Houston Hip Hop Collections
6.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The Houston Hip Hop Recording Artists Collection was started in 2010 as part of an effort to document the history of Houston Hip Hop. This collection is an artificial collection and incorporates smaller collections donated by DJs, rappers, business owners, and the hip hop community. SoSouth was particularly helpful in starting this collection.
Historical Note:
Special Collections collects and preserves historically significant materials. Its holdings comprise a rare book collection and ten main archival collecting areas. In some instances, Special Collections gathers materials on a single topic to preserve them and make them available. In these cases, Special Collections is seen as the creator of the artificially constructed collection.
The Houston Hip Hop Collecting Area was launched in 2010. Its associated collections document and preserve the history of Houston hip hop through the papers of rappers and DJs, as well as the records of related businesses.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Ephemera; Posters
Topical Term:
Hip-hop -- Texas -- Houston; Rap (Music) -- Texas -- Houston; Rap musicians -- Texas -- Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
The Houston Hip Hop Recording Artists Collection was started in 2010 as part of an effort to document the history of Houston Hip Hop. This collection is an artificial collection and incorporates smaller collections donated by DJs, rappers, business owners, and the hip hop community. SoSouth was particularly helpful in starting this collection.
The collection is divided into four series: Promotional Material, Publications, Personal Material, and Photographs. The Promotional Materials contains the bulk of the collection and is further subdivided into eight subseries by format: Posters, Poster Flats, Flyers, Event Cards and Memorabilia, Cards, Promotional Kits, Photographs, and Memorabilia.
Acquisition details:
Materials were donated by a variety of individuals and businesses, including SoSouth, Richard Johnson, K-Rino, Thomas Molinar, Jr., Screwed Up Records and Tapes, Dat Boi T, White Tim, Ace Deuce, El Franco Lee II, Terry Moore, Ariel Santschi, and Lil C.
Note: Information about the donor for specific items may be available upon request. Please contact Houston Hip Hop Collections curator Julie Grob by emailing jgrob@uh.edu for more information.
Detailed List of Contents
- Promotional Material
  Scope and Contents
  The Promotional Material series is further subdivided into subseries by format, including posters, poster flats, flyers, promotional cards picked up at specific area events, other promotional cards, promotional kits, and other assorted memorabilia. Promotional photographs have been moved to a separate Photographs series.
  - Posters, approximately 1995-2011
    The Posters subseries is divided into two sub-subseries. The Artists and Labels sub-subseries is indexed by the artist or label; most of the artists and labels poster files contain one to four posters.
    - Posters for Artists and Labels
      - 20-2-Life (Ovs box 1, Folder 1)
      - Ace Deuce (Ovs box 1, Folder 2)
      - Agony Life (Ovs box 1, Folder 3-4)
      - Backwoodz Records (Ovs box 1, Folder 5)
      - Beatbox Records (Ovs box 1, Folder 6)
      - Botany Boys (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 1, Folder 7)
      - Bun B (Ovs box 1, Folder 8)
      - Chingo Bling (Ovs box 1, Folder 9)
      - Da Underdawgs (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 1, Folder 10)
      - Dat Boi T (Screwed Up Essay poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 1, Folder 11)
      - DJ Screw (DJ Screw art poster and Diary of the Originator poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 1, Folder 12)
      - DJ Screw (Ovs box 1, Folder 13-15)
      - G-Rapp the General (Ovs box 1, Folder 16)
      - Grit Boy Gang (Ovs box 1, Folder 17)
      - HAWK (Ovs box 1, Folder 18)
      - Herschelwood Hardheadz (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 1, Folder 19)
      - J-Dawg (Ovs box 1, Folder 20)
      - KB Da Kidnappa (Ovs box 1, Folder 21)
      - K-Rino (Ovs box 1, Folder 22)
      - Lil C (Ovs box 1, Folder 23)
      - Lil’ Flip (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 1, Folder 24)
      - Lil’ O (Ovs box 1, Folder 25)
      - Macc Grace (Ovs box 1, Folder 26)
      - Mike Jones (Ovs box 1, Folder 27-28)
      - OG Avery, Big Pokey, and Lil C (Ovs box 1, Folder 29)
      - Paul Wall (Ovs box 2, Folder 1)
      - Paul Wall for Algierz Gear (Ovs box 2, Folder 2)
      - Peter Role (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 2, Folder 3)
      - Pharoah (Ovs box 2, Folder 4)
      - Playa’s Dynasty (Ovs box 2, Folder 5)
      - Point Blank (Ovs box 2, Folder 6)
      - PSK-13 (Ovs box 2, Folder 7)
      - S.L.A.B. and Point Blank (Ovs box 2, Folder 8)
      - Scarface (Ovs box 2, Folder 9)
      - Screwed Up Click (S.U.C.) (Ovs box 2, Folder 10)
      - Screwed Up Records and Tapes (Ovs box 2, Folder 11)
      - Showtyme (Ovs box 2, Folder 12)
      - South Park Mexican (Ovs box 2, Folder 13)
      - South Park Psycho (Ovs box 2, Folder 14)
      - Street Military (Ovs box 2, Folder 15-16)
      - T-Pop (Ovs box 2, Folder 17)
      - Trae tha Truth (Ovs box 2, Folder 18)
      - Underground Kingz (UGK) (Ovs box 2, Folder 19)
      - Wee Dogg (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 2, Folder 20)
      - Woss Ness (Ovs box 2, Folder 21)
      - X-Mann (Ovs box 2, Folder 22)
      - Yung Redd and Lil Ron (Ovs box 2, Folder 23)
      - Yungstar (Poster originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 2, Folder 24)
      - Z-Ro, Lil C, and J-Dawg (Ovs box 2, Folder 25)
    - General Media Posters
      - Boyz N Blue: The DVD (Ovs box 2, Folder 26)
      - Pimp Mob Records: All in the Family (Ovs box 2, Folder 27)
      - Pitch Control TV (Ovs box 2, Folder 28)
      - Texan Wire Wheels (Ovs box 2, Folder 29)
      - Savini Styling Group (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 3)
  - Poster Flats, approximately 1994-2010
    Poster flats are promotional items that are the same size and shape as vinyl album sleeves and include an album’s cover artwork.
    - Big Mello, Wegonefunkwichamind (Ovs box 2, Folder 31, Item 1)
    - DJ Screw, The Legend (Ovs box 2, Folder 31, Item 2)
    - Ganxsta N.I.P., Psych’ Swag “Da Horror Movie” (Ovs box 2, Folder 31, Item 3)
    - Tupac Shakur “2Pac” (Poster flat originally hung on the wall of the original Screwed Up Records and Tapes store at 7717 Cullen Boulevard) (Ovs box 2, Folder 31, Item 4)
  - Flyers, 2000, undated
    - DJ Screw flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
    - HAWK Under HAWK’s Wings flyer, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
    - K-Rino flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Event Cards, 2010-2013
    - Dub Car Show, May 30, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, May 19, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - SoSouth, May 26, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dub Car Show, May 30, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Johnny Dang, Galleria, June 20, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, July 28, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, September 9, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, October 29, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bigtyme Recordz, King’s Flea Market, October 29, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Unsorted, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - K-Rino and Justice Allah Album Release Party, Jet Lounge, January 22, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, April 15, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Paul Wall, Dub Car Show, May 22, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dub Car Show, May 22, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, July 31, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - K-Rino Concert, Numbers Night Club, August 6, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - K-Rino Album Release, August 6, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Unsorted, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hip Hop the Vote, University of Houston, November 2, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Unsorted, [2010-2013] (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bigtyme Recordz, King’s Flea Market, July 1, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Beatbox Records, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - SoSouth, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [SoSouth?], undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes Business Cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified Donors, [2010-2013] (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Houston SLAB Parade and Family Festival, October 20, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, April 5, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Promotional Cards, undated
    - Cards donated by Beatbox Records, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Cards donated by SoSouth, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes original store business cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Promotional Kits, 1998, 2002
    - Scarface press kit from Def Jam South for “The Fix”, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - Geto Boys press kit for “Da Good da Bad & da Ugly", 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Assorted Memorabilia, undated
    - Dat Boi T, Screwed Up Essay t-shirt (Ovs box 3, Item 1)
    - K-Rino, South Park Coalition t-shirt (Ovs box 3, Item 2)
    - El Franco Lee II, Riding Dirty and R.I.P. to various artists t-shirt (Ovs box 3, Item 3)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes, Screwed Up Click towel (Ovs box 3, Item 4)
    - Paul Wall The People’s Champ bobblehead (Ovs box 3, Item 5)
    - DJ Screw koozie (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 1)
    - Screwed Up Records and Tapes sticker (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 2)
    - Street Military stickers and buttons (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 3)
    - Four Anti-Energy drinks, marketed to imitate purple drank, or syrup (Room 261, Item 1)
- Photographs
  - 20-2-Life promotional photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - K-Rino promotional photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Point Blank promotional photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - South Park Mexican promotional photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - Underground Kingz (UGK) promotional photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - Wreckless Klan promotional photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - Screwed Up Records and Tapes (Ovs box 2, Folder 32-33)
  - Turntables (Ovs box 2, Folder 34)
- Publications
  - K-Rino publication, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - Assorted Houston hip hop magazines, undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - “Informant” catalog for Southwest Wholesale, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - K-Rino publication, 2008 (Ovs box 2, Folder 35, Item 1)
  - Trae the Truth Houston Press feature, 2010 (Ovs box 2, Folder 35, Item 2)
  - Assorted newspaper clippings, 2007, undated (Ovs box 2, Folder 35, Item 3)
- Personal Material
  - Kenneth D. Moore “Big Moe” obituary (memorial service program), October 14, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)